[Flourished Peony]
[Episode 30]
My lord, the bride has arrived.
♫ In endless Chang'an,
the zither's melody distant ♫
♫ Plum and willow trees bask in the sunshine,
as splendor returns with the year ♫
♫ Copper palace battlements,
songs and dances, glass goblets ♫
♫ Idle clouds and duckweed,
a thousand flowers burst forth ♫
♫ Time passes gracefully,
affairs settle like fading smoke ♫
♫ Let the years go by,
carried by the wind to early desires ♫
Where is your poetry for removing the fan?
I seldom see you in this attire,
and for a moment, my mind went blank.
I forgot it.
We can let it slide
with the fan-removing ritual.
There's still the washing ritual.
The couple
wash together at the same time
to signify purity.
♫ The distant night sky strewn with stars,
reflecting the lovely moon ♫
♫ The peony's magnificent beauty
fills the Fragrance Garden ♫
♫ With a heart as my lantern,
I don't mind the distant mountain paths ♫
♫ The flute's sound,
a fleeting life's wishes fulfilled ♫
♫ Time passes gracefully,
affairs settle like fading smoke ♫
Don't play with me. This makeup
took a long time for Chun and Fu
to put on.
Mr. Xu, look at her.
Shut up.
Just wipe your hands.
♫ Still cherish the moon of my hometown,
to meet for long ♫
Next is the joint meal ritual.
The couple
share the meat of the same animal,
symbolizing that the two
are united as one family,
sharing weal and woe, supporting each other.
Choose one.
In joint meal and united cups,
husband and wife are one.
Two hearts joined as a whole.
Eternal happiness and prosperity.
What else is there? Mother.
Hair braiding, and bridal chamber.
- Bridal chamber.
As for the final step,
we won't skimp on it.
The bridal chamber's charm
lies in mutual affection.
With everyone watching so attentively,
it's perhaps not quite proper.
I am of an old age.
I cannot look upon these juvenile affections.
You can watch.
Remember to cultivate oneself
and follow ceremonies.
That's how this joyous event
can be perfectly blissful.
Me too.
I'm of a certain age now.
I won't join in this bustle.
Have a good time in the bridal chamber.
♫ If the heart is like frost ♫
♫ Congealing so much of the past ♫
♫ It sinks into your gaze ♫
♫ Melting and flowing with you ♫
♫ If love is like frost ♫
♫ Can this ten thousand miles
of roaming winds and waves ♫
♫ Can it ♫
♫ Finally touch a sunny day ♫
Is it heavy?
Should I help you
take it off?
♫ Fleecy clouds in the sky ♫
♫ Seeking a place to rest ♫
♫ The moon falls on my shoulder,
a path of dim yellow ♫
♫ Silk grows, sprouting longing ♫
♫ If the heart is like frost ♫
♫ What's the harm in a life of solitude ♫
♫ Yet you shine as light ♫
♫ Piercing through my heart ♫
♫ If love is like frost ♫
♫ There's a flickering candle ♫
♫ No words are said ♫
♫ Yet for you ♫
♫ I'll go ahead ♫
Then, I'll help you take it off, too.
Old Xu says
we must cultivate ourselves
and follow ceremonies.
Right, right.
♫ Snow lashes against thorns and wilds ♫
Comb once to the end,
no need to worry about wealth and honor.
Then you should comb more.
Comb until we're the richest under the heavens.
♫ A thousand lines of yearning ♫
Comb twice to the end,
no illness and no worries.
This sounds pretty good, too.
Comb thrice to the tip.
♫ Flowers bloom and fall ♫
♫ Only wishing for you ♫
Mutual love and respect.
United heart jade
with a beginning and an end,
means being wealthy together in this life.
I promise you the last line.
Together wealthy in this life.
I'll never go back on my word.
Me too.
Can we skip this one?
It hasn't been easy
for my hair to grow out.
Let's skip it.
Anyway,
I entrust this lock of my hair to you,
if you comb out some hair
and are willing to gather it and tuck it in,
we can consider it as having joined hair.
This sounds somewhat scary.
My aunt traveled by boat to a foreign land.
Upon learning that she missed
our wedding feast,
she was furious.
She ordered her men to speed up the horses
and deliver this congratulatory gift to you.
It's not some valuable item anyway.
It happens that you've recently
opened a new shop,
tired with disheveled hair and dim strands.
Combing more can also reduce some headaches.
Okay, then I will sponge off your aunt's
fortune of being wealthy without restraint.
This comb looks really beautiful,
exquisite in appearance.
Chun is currently developing
Yunbin Pill that could make
a woman's hair lush.
I can make a batch of sandalwood
ones according to this pattern
and sell them in a set.
Wouldn't we make even more money this way?
Sandalwood not only has
the effect of preventing hair loss
but also can reduce wind-heat,
swelling, and pain.
It perfectly matches my Yunbin Pill.
A token of love is important.
How can he send her off with a comb?
I'll tell you a secret.
But you must not spread it around.
This comb
is a treasured item of the young master.
Its worth is not about the price.
It was a personal belonging
of my lord's late mother.
The lady once said when she was still alive,
if her son were to marry in the future,
she must gift this item to the bride,
hoping that my lord and his wife
could be united in marriage and heart
and grow old together.
The united-hair ceremony is complete.
As for the bridal chamber to follow,
if you continue to eavesdrop here,
I won't have mercy.
Yes.
Let's go.
My mother mentioned the bridal chamber.
Are we not watching anymore?
Wait, we're watching the bridal chamber.
Why aren't you watching anymore?
Come on over.
Come on.
The Bureau of Beds
is quite wealthy
to scatter so much money around.
What a pity it's not Kaiyuan Tongbao.
Otherwise, we could have made a big profit.
These specially made money for scattering
aim for good luck
and a harmonious union.
It's not for you to fixate on the money.
I'm hungry too.
Let's eat together.
That's great.
I'm starving.
However you were before,
you must remain so in the future.
No need to act all prim and proper
because you married a high official.
You needn't mind those empty
titles and ceremonies.
As for your business dealings,
you can continue as before.
If any censor impeaches,
I'll handle it.
The last time I married, it was real.
But the wedding
was utterly absurd.
I suppress my true nature every day,
pretending to be the virtuous
and proper Young Madam of the Liu family
without a single day of joy.
But this time,
although it's a sham marriage,
I can be the real He Weifang.
To find a true friend in life
is enough.
Yes, indeed.
Let's drink.
If in the future,
you meet someone you truly love.
Rest assured,
I won't take the bet money.
I will personally write a letter of release.
I will definitely not mess up your good match.
Sure.
My lord.
Go away.
Although you are marrying into the family,
at the wedding banquet, His Majesty decreed
to promote you to Deputy Transport
Officer of all regions.
This position controls the grain transport.
It's exactly what you were hoping for.
You can make your mark in the days to come.
How am I different
from He Weifang when she married
into the Liu family in the past?
Officials trample on merchants.
Royal relatives trample on officials.
One layer oppresses another.
♫ Helpless, to draw the sword
and cut through water ♫
If one does not climb to the highest place,
one will forever be meat on the chopping block.
My lord, don't say that.
You're scaring me.
Scared?
What are you scared of?
I will be a good son-in-law.
I will manage
the grain transport well.
My lord.
Your leg can't stand the cold.
It's just a few vases of flowers.
You don't know.
These flowers
can't be rained on.
My Lord.
Peonies can't be rained upon.
But this is a Thousand-Petal Lotus.
The blooming period has passed.
The peonies are long gone.
♫ How much love goes against desire ♫
♫ How many different paths
lead to the same end ♫
♫ Upon turning around, who is still there ♫
Thousand-Petal Lotus?
Thousand-leaf precious lotus.
Manifested as the Tathagata.
If there truly are gods and Buddhas,
do they know of my suffering?
Will they save me?
♫ If I never come back ♫
My Lord.
♫ Waiting for the flowers to bloom ♫
Tell the entire household.
Don't let me see a single peony
or a petal of a lotus
in the mansion.
Yes.
[…]
My lord is looking bright and spirited today.
Congratulations to my lord
for finding a match made in heaven,
wishing you lasting fortune.
Congratulations to my lord
on your joyous wedding,
wishing you continuous harmony.
Smooth talker.
I like it.
Reward.
- Thank you, My lord.
Congratulations my lord, my best wishes to you.
Reward.
- Congratulations, my lord.
- Best wishes to my lord.
Reward them all.
- Thank you, My lord.
Watch your step.
The bridal chamber was last night,
and they are moving today.
Can this
young madam be more heartless?
Fu.
Where is Mudan?
What are you doing?
Mudan went early in the morning
to refurbish the Fragrance Garden.
I will move to live there from now on.
During this period,
thank you, Mr. Jiang, for everything.
Let's go.
See you around.
She's moving out?
I thought the Fragrance Garden was only
for sightseeing and doing business.
If she misses it,
she can just move there and stay
for a few days now and then, right?
I sneaked off to see the Fragrance Garden.
There are many houses over there,
with pavilions, waterside galleries,
mountains built, and lakes pierced through.
Indeed, it is much more comfortable
than living in this small courtyard.
My lord, are you
reluctant to let the young lady leave?
What do you mean?
We married yesterday,
and she's moving out today.
Where is the face of me, the Floral Envoy?
Luckily, there are quite a few
furnishings in the house.
It can't be all moved in a short time.
Hurry to Fragrance Garden
and keep an eye on it for me.
What should I say
when I see the young lady?
Should I say you are reluctant to let her go
and want to ask her to come back?
Or do I say
that moving away the day after the wedding
is against propriety.
Just say
that she has regained the garden,
and I, her husband, am happy for her.
But the garden refurbishment involves
many people and is complicated.
I'm afraid that she will overexert herself.
So I am willing to lend a hand.
Understood.
Slow down.
[Flower Cultivating Soil]
Come, give me a hand.
- Coming, three, two, one.
- Be careful.
Mudan, let's go there together.
Be careful.
Come on.
If we could let those who are
keen on admiring flowers
all enter the garden to take in
the full view of the blossoming beauty.
Mother's spirit in heaven
must be very pleased.
Young lady.
The renovation of the old garden
is a complex affair.
Whether it's labor or materials,
the lord is willing to help out.
Reconstruction of the Fragrance Garden
requires personal involvement.
Only then can I truly feel
the joy of regaining what was lost.
Moreover,
Mr. Jiang has already helped me a lot.
I shall take care of
the refurbishing of the garden myself.
No need to trouble Mr. Jiang any further.
It's not good.
It's bad. It's bad.
- What's wrong?
- This is bad.
What happened? Why are you panicking?
An old servant of this garden heard
that the garden was going to change ownership.
They refuse to leave
and are threatening to hang themselves.
Where are they?
Over there, hurry, move quickly!
Let go of me, let me go!
Come down quickly!
Let go of me, release me!
- It's her, it's her.
- Make way, please.
Let go of me, release me!
Release me, what's wrong with you?
Leave me alone.
Move aside, move aside!
Everyone step back, it's nothing.
Don't worry about her.
Go ahead and hang.
Why are you stopping?
This hemp rope has a slipknot.
It's impossible to die from it.
If you truly wish to seek death,
it's more convenient to hang
from the beam at night.
Madam, please feel free
to say what you want to do.
So, you are Lady He.
You're young,
but how can you be so mean?
I just arrived.
I haven't said or done anything yet.
You come up and try
to intimidate me right away.
Should I still be pleasant to you?
You are obviously a perceptive person.
So I'll just speak frankly.
I've been attending to this garden for so long.
Whenever the ownership changes,
they want to drive me away.
But now I'm old.
I don't want to be troubled anymore.
I earnestly request that you,
madam, let me stay.
I've investigated the details of all
previous servants of this garden
on my lord's orders.
This woman's surname is Tang,
known as Madam Tang.
When the previous owner sold the garden,
she was dismissed.
But later,
when Guild Head Lv took over,
she also made a scene
by pretending to hang herself once.
Guild Head Lv couldn't win against her,
so he agreed to let her stay.
Madam Tang is so reluctant to leave this place,
sparing no effort in seeking death.
- Perhaps there is some other hidden affair?
- I…
This Madam Tang has a son.
Last year, because he committed
theft in the county lieutenant's residence.
He left her alone to avoid disaster.
And so far, there has been no news.
My son was framed.
He abandoned me only to escape the trouble.
This damned kid will surely come back.
My lady.
This is the home of my son and me.
If I leave,
he won't be able to find me anymore
when he returns one day.
I earnestly request you to let me stay.
Please keep me here, please.
Madam Tang, please get up quickly.
Get up quickly.
Madame, I am not cold-hearted.
I also pity the kind heart of a mother.
But business is business.
I am renovating the Fragrance Garden
to provide a place for guests
to relax and enjoy the flowers.
Food, wine, music, and scenery
all require meticulous care.
We're renovating today and running
a business in the future.
If you are truly capable,
of course, I will keep you.
But if not…
Since you are running a business,
there must be a need for a steward.
I used to be
the stewardess of this garden,
managing purchases for over a hundred people
without a single mistake.
Stewardship talents
are not rare.
What about hiring people?
My father came from a craftsman background.
All of Chang'an's artisans,
whether they are tilers,
embroiderers, or musicians,
no one doesn't give face to Madam Tang.
Mudan, our garden is undergoing
renovation and opening.
We indeed need quite a number of workers.
And you have high requirements for this.
Why not give her a chance to try?
What kind of person do you want?
Just tell me anything.
Give me three days,
and if I cannot gather the talent you want,
I'll move out myself.
Okay.
Then I'll give you three days.
Thank you, Shopkeeper. Thank you, Shopkeeper.
Just tell me directly
what you want in the future.
Don't make a fuss anymore.
Fine, now, my lord
has lost the opportunity
to help find workers as well.
She hasn't returned for two days.
She should come back tonight, right?
After all, these flowers in the garden
should be taken away, right?
My lord, Prince Ning has arrived.
He says he's here to congratulate
you on taking a concubine,
bringing several boxes of treasures.
My lady has been impertinent
to the County Princess,
and it's proper for me to make amends.
How dare I trouble Your Highness to visit?
I'm afraid it is overflattering for her.
The injury of Youzhen
is ultimately because that horse
was unruly and hard to tame.
How can a lowly animal let me
become estranged from Suizhi?
Suizhi.
You finally have a companion.
I am very pleased.
Therefore, this gift is deserved.
However,
this most precious one
requires you
to open it personally.
Suizhi, don't panic.
Lianzhou, come out.
Mr. Jiang.
Your Highness, what is this?
You once said you were unwilling to marry,
but now you have already taken a concubine.
One more isn't too many.
It's double happiness arriving at the doorstep.
Moreover, it ensures
the continuation of descendants.
Your deceased parents would be pleased.
I think
His Majesty would also be delighted.
Dear husband,
my name is Lianzhou.
My needlework, qin skills and dance skills
have all been trained by masters
invited by His Highness.
As for etiquette and norms,
I have thoroughly practiced
them in the royal household.
I will surely manage the household well
and nurture your mind and spirit
in the future.
Lady Lianzhou is charming and moving,
unparalleled in beauty and art,
a wonderful person.
However, you might not know this,
but my young lady is a jealous type.
I've just taken a concubine three days ago.
And now I am welcoming another
new beauty to my home.
I'm afraid…
I'm afraid the days ahead will not be easy.
If a concubine is prone to jealousy,
that would be disrespecting the lord.
This is indecorous.
Lianzhou.
You must teach her well when the time comes.
Yes.
Suizhi.
In the past, I granted you a marriage,
and you refused it.
Now,
I'm giving you my most beloved foster daughter
as your concubine.
If you refuse again,
do you truly wish to alienate yourself from me?
How could that be?
I hold Your Highness in high regard,
which is why I worry
that Lady Lianzhou will be wronged.
She won't be.
This time, I have even
prepared the banquet
for you and Lianzhou.
Enter.
A few days ago,
you didn't even hold a banquet
for your taking in a concubine.
Today, you and Lianzhou
have a great celebration.
I have specially arranged for the most
capable servant in my mansion
to personally manage it.
It will certainly show
the dignity of both households.
You are so thoughtful, Your Highness.
Presumably, the invitations
for the wedding feast
have also been sent out.
Suizhi, you are naturally carefree,
unwilling to be entangled
in these trivial matters.
So I have taken care of it on your behalf.
Moreover,
I have calculated it.
This morning
is simply
an extremely auspicious day.
Suizhi,
what do you say?
Thank you, Your Highness.
Thank you, My lord.
In the future,
I will surely serve my husband
with all my heart.
To let your little boys and girls
be at ease,
I will not join the banquet tonight.
Lianzhou.
At the banquet,
you must pay great respect
to that jealous lady.
Yes.
Mr. Jiang.
I am still hungover.
I'm unreliable.
Unreliable.
That Madam Tang is really capable.
We switched to the craftsmen she found.
They are very handy.
She has some good bargaining skills
which saved us quite a bit of money.
Let's go and see first.
Okay.
Shopkeeper.
Greetings, everyone.
As per your request,
I have found them for you.
This is the qin player, Tao.
Greetings, Shopkeeper.
Tao, all sorts of instruments
like pipa, lusheng, konghou,
anything you can name,
there is nothing she can't play.
This is the embroiderer, Aman.
Greetings, Shopkeeper.
Aman can do straight and loop stitches.
She is also skilled at stitching
and spinning needles.
Anything you can see can be embroidered.
Jinniang excels in fine cooking techniques
and especially at making wine.
Greetings.
Jinniang.
As for their skills,
you will know once you try.
Tao, come on.
Aman.
Fu.
I'm asking you to appreciate the embroidery.
It smells good.
Jinniang, the wine.
It tastes good.
This wine is called 'Flowers Wine'.
Good wine.
Though I lack talent,
I can see that the three of you
possess exquisite skills,
worthy of being considered
experts in the field.
Why would you be willing to condescend
and come to the Fragrance Garden?
I'm afraid if I say the truth,
you might disdain me.
Shopkeeper, you are unaware.
Jinniang was pawned by her husband
and passed through several hands.
Now she's working at a tavern.
Although she has craftsmanship,
she is envied by her peers.
Because of her gender,
she is belittled by the tavern owner.
Without reclaiming her deed of sale,
she cannot leave.
Tao was originally a noble's daughter,
skilled in zither, chess,
calligraphy, and painting.
But due to her family being convicted,
she was reduced to a low status overnight.
Though a musician, she is without
worries for food and clothing,
she is unwilling to mingle among men every day.
Hearing that the Fragrance Garden
has a female owner,
she naturally wants to make a living here.
As for Aman,
her embroidery skills are excellent,
yet she was sold by her gambler father
into Pingkang House,
unable to utilize her skills.
She has always been saving money
to buy back her freedom.
She asked several embroidery workshops,
but they all refused her because of her status.
Her heart was despondent
until she heard that the Fragrance
Garden was hiring.
I see.
Being a woman,
many things are difficult
to do.
But not everyone
is as brave as you.
After hearing all this,
I have even more respect for the three of you.
Shopkeeper, are you saying
you want to keep them here?
I will go to your current master's place
and redeem your indentures
so you can work with me in the future
and no longer suffer the cold
stares of the world
or be bullied by men.
Thank you so much for your
great kindness, Shopkeeper.
What are you doing?
Get up quickly.
Get up quickly, get up. Please stand.
Everyone, get up.
I am not looking for servants
but for partners who share my aspirations.
As long as you give your all
and show your sincerity
in building the Fragrance Garden with me,
I will surely treat you
generously in the future.
We are willing to lay down our lives
and devote our utmost to help.
Mudan is right.
We, the sons and daughters
of the martial world.
We recognize only the bond of sisterhood.
There are no masters or servants, high or low.
In the future, at this place,
if anyone dares to bully you,
I'll beat him up.
Her fist is really formidable.
She will surely be able to protect
you in the future.
I am truly happy today.
After buying back Fragrance Garden
and achieving my wish,
I felt somewhat lost.
But seeing you all today
has given me new hopes.
In the future, I want
to open more shops
so that people like us
can all have a place to belong.
We can use our abilities
to seek wealth and honor together.
On the day I was sold,
I told myself I had no relatives left.
I never expected to meet someone like you.
Don't be sad.
Today is an auspicious day for starting work.
Everyone, come to our house tonight
and have a feast together
to celebrate starting the work, okay?
Okay!
Let's eat meat and drink wine.
Let's drink Flowers Banquet.
- Okay.
- Alright.
It's Flowers Wine.
Flowers Wine.
♫ In endless Chang'an,
the zither's melody distant ♫
♫ Plum and willow trees bask in the sunshine,
as splendor returns with the year ♫
♫ Copper palace battlements,
songs and dances, glass goblets ♫
♫ Idle clouds and duckweed,
a thousand flowers burst forth ♫
♫ Time passes gracefully,
affairs settle like fading smoke ♫
♫ Let the years go by,
carried by the wind to early desires ♫
♫ If the heart is like water,
the bloom is ever-present ♫
♫ Still cherish the moon of my hometown,
to meet for long ♫
♫ The distant night sky strewn with stars,
reflecting the lovely moon ♫
♫ The peony's magnificent beauty
fills the Fragrance Garden ♫
♫ With a heart as my lantern,
I don't mind the distant mountain paths ♫
♫ The flute's sound,
a fleeting life's wishes fulfilled ♫
♫ Time passes gracefully,
affairs settle like fading smoke ♫
♫ Let the years go by,
carried by the wind to early desires ♫
♫ If the heart is like water,
the bloom is ever-present ♫
♫ Still cherish the moon of my hometown,
to meet for long ♫